A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1987-1988
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files RG-2/1/2.901
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.901
This collection consists of 12,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 1990 August 14.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by Robert O'Neil, the President of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general files, 1987-1988; seldom used permanent files, 1984-1987; administrative committee files, 1987-1988; and, files on background materials for speeches, 1985-1987.
Organization
Series I: General Files, 1987-1988 Boxes 1-46
Series II: Seldom Used Permanent Files, 1984-1987 Boxes 46-51
Series III: Administrative Committee Files, 1987-1988 Boxes 51-52
Series IV: Background Materials for Speeches, 1985-1987 Boxes 53-55
Series V: Restricted Materials Boxes 56-57
Contents List
- Series I: General Files
  - "A" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Administration--General 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Computing Services 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--General 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--Law 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--Medical 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - African-American Affairs 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - African-American Affairs--Woodson Institute 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association--General 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Alumni and Friends Letter (2 folders) 1987 Feb-1988 Jan (Box 2)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities (AASCU)--General 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - American Association of University Professors (AAUP)--General 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - American Bar Association (ABA) (3 folders) 1987-1988 Jan-Jun (Box 3)
  - American Bar Association (ABA) (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - American Council on Education (ACE)--General 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - American Frontier Culture Foundation (AFCF)--General 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - Annual Reports--President's Reports 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - Anthropology--General 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - Architecture--General 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Art--General 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Art--Bayly Museum 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Asian Studies (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Associated Western Universities 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Association of American Colleges (AAC)--General (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Association of American Colleges (AAC)--"SCAN" (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU) (5 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 6)
  - AAU-- Executive Committee 1987-1988 (Box 6)
  - AAU (2 folders) 1987 (Box 6)
  - Association of Governing Boards (AGB) 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Association of Research Libraries (ARL) 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges (AVC) 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Astronomy--General 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Athletics--General (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Athletics--All-American Bowl 1987 Dec 22 (Box 8)
  - Athletics--Atlantic Coast Conference (ACC) 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Athletics--College Football Association (CFA) 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Athletics--Finances 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Athletics--National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Athletics--Personnel (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Attorney General (State)--General 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Attorney General (State)--Foundation Requests (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Auditor--Internal 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1987-1988 (Box 9)
  - "B" Miscellaneous (6 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 9)
  - Biology--General 1987-1988 (Box 10)
  - Birdwood--General 1987-1988 (Box 10)
  - Business and Finance--General 1987-1988 (Box 10)
  - Business and Finance--Vice Presidential Planning Group 1987-1988 (Box 10)
  - Business Operations (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 10)
  - "C" Miscellaneous (1-4 of 12) 1987-1988 (Box 10)
  - "C" Miscellaneous (5-12 of 12) 1987-1988 (Box 11)
  - Career Planning and Placement 1987-1988 (Box 12)
  - Cavalier Daily (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 12)
  - Center for Innovative Technology (CIT)-- (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 12)
  - Charlottesville, City of--General 1987-1988 (Box 12)
  - Charlottesville, City of--Planning and Coordination Council 1987-1988 (Box 12)
  - Chemistry--General 1987-1988 (Box 12)
  - China 1987-1988 (Box 12)
  - Civil Rights--General (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 12)
  - Classics--General 1987-1988 (Box 12)
  - Clinch Valley College--General 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - College of Arts and Sciences--General 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - College Board 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Commerce--General 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Community Colleges (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Comptroller (State)--General 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Condolences: A-Z 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Congress--General 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--Capital 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--General (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--Central Virginia 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--Northern Virginia 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--Tidewater 1987-1988 (Box 14)
  - Consortia--Valley 1987-1988 (Box 14)
  - Consortia--Western 1987-1988 (Box 14)
  - Continuing Education 1987-1988 (Box 14)
  - Council of Presidents 1987-1988 (Box 14)
  - Council of Southern Universities (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 14)
  - Council on Postsecondary Accreditation (COPA) (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 14)
  - COPA--Task Force on Educational Quality 1987-1988 (Box 14)
  - COPA--Educational Quality and Accreditation (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 14)
  - COPA--Board Meeting 1987 (Box 15)
  - "D" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 15)
  - Darden Graduate School of Business Administration 1987-1988 (Box 15)
  - Darden Graduate School of Business Administration--Darden Business Sponsors 1987-1988 (Box 15)
  - Deans' Meetings 1987-1988 (Box 16)
  - Development--General (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 16)
  - Development--Internal Development Group (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 16)
  - Development--Proposals Pending (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 16)
  - Drama 1987-1988 (Box 16)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 16)
  - Economics 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - Education--General 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - Education--Ward, Virgil (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - Educational Testing Service--Minutes (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - Energy Policy Studies Center (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - Engineering and Applied Science--Engineering Development Council 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - Engineering Buildings-- State 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - English--General 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - English Graduate Teaching Assistants Letters (2 folders) 1988 (Box 17)
  - Enrollment--General 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - Environmental Sciences 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - Equal Opportunity Office--General 1987-1988 (Box 18)
  - "F" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 18)
  - Faculty--General 1987-1988 (Box 18)
  - Faculty Budget Letter (2 folders) 1988 Jan-Feb (Box 18)
  - Faculty Letter (2 folders) 1987 Sep-Dec (Box 18)
  - Faculty Retirees Dinner-- Board of Visitors 1988 Mar 17 (Box 19)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - Faculty Forum for Scientific Research 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - Food Services 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - French--General 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - "G" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - General Assembly (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly-- Appropriations (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly-- Legislative Summaries (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 20)
  - General Services 1987-1988 (Box 20)
  - German--General 1987-1988 (Box 20)
  - Gifts and Grants (1-2 of 10) 1987-1988 (Box 20)
  - Gifts and Grants (3-8 of 10) 1987-1988 (Box 21)
  - Gifts and Grants (9-10 of 10) 1987-1988 (Box 22)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1987-1988 (Box 22)
  - Governmental Relations--General 1987-1988 (Box 22)
  - Governmental Relations--Barnes, Dennis (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 22)
  - Governor's Office--General 1987-1988 (Box 22)
  - Governor's Office--Administration 1987-1988 (Box 22)
  - Governor's Office--Commerce and Resources 1987-1988 (Box 22)
  - Governor's Office--Decentralization Task Force 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Governor's Office--Education 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Governor's Office--Finance 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Governor's Office--Human Resources 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Governor's Office--Task Force on Science and Technology (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Governor's Office--Transportation and Public Safety 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Governor's Office--Virginia/Israel Commission 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Governor's Office--Washington Liaison Office 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences--General 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences-- GSAS-- Advisory Committee on Career Opportunities (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - "H" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 5) 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - "H" Miscellaneous (4-5 of 5) 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - Harrison Foundation 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - Higher Education of 1965 (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - Higher Education of 1965--Title I (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - Higher Education of 1965--Title III (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - Higher Education of 1965--Title IV (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - Higher Education of 1965--Title IX (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - History--General 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - Honor System--General 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - Housing 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - "I" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - Information Technology--State 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - Institute of Government 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - Institutional Planning and Studies (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - International Students 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - "J" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation (TJMF)--General 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - Jeffersonian Restoration Board Committee Newsletter 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - Jeffersonian Restoration Advisory Board--General (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC) 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - Kluge 1987-1988 (Box 26)
  - "L" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 26)
  - Law--General (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 26)
  - Lawn Use Policy (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 27)
  - Lawn Society Advisory Group (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 27)
  - Legal Advisor's Office--General 1987-1988 (Box 27)
  - Library--General 1987-1988 (Box 27)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1987-1988 (Box 27)
  - "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous (1 of 3) 1987-1988 (Box 27)
  - "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous (2-3 of 3) 1987-1988 (Box 28)
  - "Mf-Mz" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 28)
  - Management Analysis and Systems Development--MASD (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 29)
  - Marine Science 1987-1988 (Box 29)
  - Mariners Museum (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 29)
  - Material Management--Purchasing 1987-1988 (Box 29)
  - Mathematics 1987-1988 (Box 29)
  - Medical Center--General (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center--Council of Trustees 1987-1988 (Box 30)
  - Hospital--General 1987-1988 (Box 30)
  - Hospital--Personnel (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center--Replacement Hospital Dedication 1987-1988 (Box 30)
  - Medical School--General 1987-1988 (Box 31)
  - Medical School--Personnel (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 31)
  - Nursing--General 1987-1988 (Box 31)
  - Nursing--Personnel 1987-1988 (Box 31)
  - Music 1987-1988 (Box 31)
  - "N" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 31)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges-NASULGC --General (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 32)
  - NASULGC--Green Circulars 1987-1988 (Box 32)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) 1987-1988 (Box 32)
  - Newcomb Hall--General 1987-1988 (Box 32)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1987-1988 (Box 32)
  - Oak Ridge Associate Universities 1987-1988 (Box 32)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 32)
  - Online Computer Library Center 1987-1988 (Box 32)
  - "P" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 33)
  - Parking and Transportation--General 1987-1988 (Box 33)
  - Personnel and Training--State 1987-1988 (Box 33)
  - Personnel--General 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Philosophy 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Physical Planning (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Physical Plant 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Physical Plant--Project Status Reports (Construction Reports) 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Physics 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Planning--Miscellaneous (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Planning and Budget 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Planning and Budget-- Capital Outlay 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Planning and Budget-- Medical 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Planning and Budget-- State--General 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Planning and Budget-- State (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Planning and Budget-- University of Virginia 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Poynter Institute (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - President's Staff Meetings (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 34)
  - Promotions 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - Provost--General 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - Provost--Associate Provost for Research 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - Psychology 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - Purchases and Supply (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - "R" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - Real Estate Foundation 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - Real Estate, Risk Management and Safety--General 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - Recommendations: A-Z 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - Registrar 1987-1988 (Box 36)
  - Religious Studies (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 36)
  - Reserve Officers' Training Corps (ROTC)--General 1987-1988 (Box 36)
  - ROTC--Air Force (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 36)
  - ROTC--Army 1987-1988 (Box 36)
  - ROTC--Navy 1987-1988 (Box 36)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (1-5 of 7) 1987-1988 (Box 36)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (6-7 of 7) 1987-1988 (Box 37)
  - Senate, University--General (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 37)
  - Slavic Languages and Literatures 1987-1988 (Box 37)
  - Small Business Development Center 1987-1988 (Box 37)
  - Small Business Development Center Working Group (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 37)
  - Sociology 1987-1988 (Box 38)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (SACS) 1987-1988 (Box 38)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities-- SALGCU--(empty) 1987-1988 (Box 38)
  - Southern Regional Educational Board--General 1987-1988 (Box 38)
  - Southern Regional Educational Board--Publications (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 38)
  - Space and Energy Management (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 38)
  - Spanish, Italian, and Portuguese 1987-1988 (Box 38)
  - Sponsored Programs 1987-1988 (Box 38)
  - State Council of Higher Education of Virginia-- SCHEV (3 folders) 1988 Jan-Jun (Box 38)
  - SCHEV (3 folders) 1988 Jul-Dec (Box 39)
  - SCHEV--Assessment 1987-1988 (Box 39)
  - SCHEV--Council Notes 1987-1988 (Box 39)
  - State Council of Higher Education--SCHEV--On Line 1987-1988 (Box 39)
  - State Department of Education 1987-1988 (Box 39)
  - State Fire Marshal 1987-1988 (Box 39)
  - Student Affairs--General (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 40)
  - Student Affairs--Fraternities (empty) 1987-1988 (Box 40)
  - Student Council--General (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 40)
  - Student Council--Minutes 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - Summer Session 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - "T" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - Talyoe Murphy Institute 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - Travel Invoices 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - Treasurer 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - "U" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - "U" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - United States Savings Bonds 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - United Way 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - Universities Research Association 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - University Business Innovation Center (UBIC) 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - University Guides 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - University Journal 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - University Police 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - University Press of Virginia 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - University Relations 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - University Union (UU) 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (1 of 3) 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (2-3 of 3) 1987-1988 (Box 43)
  - Virginia Academy of Science (VAS) 1987-1988 (Box 43)
  - Virginia Festival of American Film (2 folders) 1987-1988 (Box 43)
  - Virginia Judicial System Commission (1 of 4) 1987-1988 (Box 43)
  - Virginia Judicial System Commission (2-4 of 4) 1987-1988 (Box 44)
  - Virginia Judicial System Commission--Richmond 1988 Jan (Box 44)
  - Commission of the Future of Virginia's Judicial System 1987 Dec (Box 44)
  - Virginia Judicial System Commission--Letters 1988 Jan (Box 45)
  - Virginia Judicial System Commission--Richmond 1987 Nov (Box 45)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1987-1988 (Box 45)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1987-1988 (Box 45)
  - "W" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 5) 1987-1988 (Box 45)
  - "W" Miscellaneous (4-5 of 5) 1987-1988 (Box 46)
  - "X, Y, Z" Miscellaneous 1987-1988 (Box 46)
- Series II: Seldom Used Permanent Files
  - Economic Development--Task Force on Industrial Liaison (2 folders) 1985-1987 (Box 47)
  - Economic Development--Search for Vice Provost for University-Industry Relations 1986-1987 (Box 47)
  - EOE--Affirmative Action VI (3 folders) 1986-1987 (Box 47)
  - Faculty Tenure 1985 Oct (Box 47)
  - Hereford Resignation 1984 Mar-Apr (Box 47)
  - Jeffersonian Restoration--Board II (2 folders) 1986-1987 (Box 48)
  - Lawn Society 1987 Nov (Box 48)
  - Medical Center--HMO 1987 (Box 48)
  - Miller Center for Public Affairs (3 folders) 1986 Jul-1987 Jun (Box 49)
  - Minority Affairs 1986 Jul-1987 May (Box 49)
  - Board of Visitors-- Special Committee Search for Chancellor for Clinch Valley 1987 (Box 49)
  - College (1 of 2)
  - Board of Visitors-- Special Committee Search for Chancellor for Clinch Valley 1987 (Box 50)
  - College (2 of 2)
  - Board of Visitors--General (3 folders) 1986 Jul-1987 Jun (Box 50)
  - Board of Visitors--Cremins, James S. n.d. (Box 51)
  - Board of Visitors--Dudley, Henry A. n.d. (Box 51)
  - Board of Visitors--Glover, Jerry V. (student) n.d. (Box 51)
  - Board of Visitors--Key, Glynn D. (student) n.d. (Box 51)
  - Board of Visitors--Pollard, Fred G. n.d. (Box 51)
  - Board of Visitors--Weaver, Edgar N. n.d. (Box 51)
- Series III: Administrative Committees
  - Administrative Committees--General 1987-1988 (Box 51)
  - University Committee: Arboretum and Landscape 1987-1988 (Box 51)
  - University Committee: Athletic Advisory Council 1987-1988 (Box 51)
  - University Committee: Calendar 1987-1988 (Box 51)
  - University Committee: Commencement and Convocations 1987-1988 (Box 51)
  - University Committee: Community Colleges 1987-1988 (Box 51)
  - University Committee: Computing and Communications 1987-1988 (Box 51)
  - University Committee: Development Policy 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Equal Opportunity/Affirmative Action 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Faculty Benefits 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Financial Aid 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Housing 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: International Students 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Jefferson, Thomas Award 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Libraries 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Judicial Policy 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Master Planning Council 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Names 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Proxy Advisory 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Radiation Safety 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Research Policy Advisory 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Residential Life 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Rhodes Scholarships 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Scheduling 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Security and General Safety 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Traffic Appeals 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Transportation and Parking 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Truman Scholarships 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Undergraduate Admissions 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: University Press of Virginia 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Virginia Quarterly Review 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - University Committee: Virginia Status of Students 1987-1988 (Box 52)
  - Vice President's Committees 1987-1988 (Box 52)
- Series IV: Background Material for Speeches
  - Speeches, Background Material--General n.d. (Box 53)
  - Speeches, Background Material--Alumni n.d. (Box 53)
  - Alumni Board of Managers 1986 Oct 10-11 (Box 53)
  - Arts and Sciences Advisory Council 1985 Sep 14 (Box 53)
  - AAU Testimony: Research Libraries 1985 Sep 6 (Box 53)
  - Articulation Conference--Speech Background 1986 Oct 30-31 (Box 53)
  - Black Alumni Weekend--Background Materials 1986 Apr 24-26 (Box 53)
  - Blue Ridge Rotary Breakfast 1986 Oct 15 (Box 53)
  - Clinch Valley College Inauguration 1985 Oct 22-23 (Box 53)
  - McIntire Advisory Board--Commerce 1985 Sep 27 (Box 53)
  - Constitution Bicentennial 1985 Aug 27 (Box 53)
  - Creative Management in Higher Education n.d. (Box 53)
  - Brookings Institute Conference (Nanette Blandin) 1986 Jun 20 (Box 53)
  - Darden School of Business n.d. (Box 53)
  - Darden Sponsors Trustees 1986 Oct 17 (Box 53)
  - Echols Scholars Gathering--Washington D.C. 1985 Oct 17 (Box 53)
  - Education School Retreat 1985 Aug 29 (Box 53)
  - Engineering Banquet, 150th Anniversary 1986 Oct 3 (Box 53)
  - Engineering Reception, 150th Anniversary 1985 Nov 9 (Box 54)
  - Fairfax Rotary Luncheon 1986 Oct 6 (Box 54)
  - Fall Convocation 1986 Oct 10 (Box 54)
  - General Education n.d. (Box 54)
  - Governor's Day--Background plus two speeches 1986 Oct 25 (Box 54)
  - Hampton University Convocation 1985 Sep 15 (Box 54)
  - University of Illinois Retreat 1986 Feb 12 (Box 54)
  - Inauguration Week 1985 Oct 2 (Box 54)
  - International Education n.d. (Box 54)
  - Decker Lecture at JAG School 1986 Apr 24 (Box 54)
  - Leadership Charlottesville 1986 Sep 17 (Box 54)
  - Le Figaro--Speeches n.d. (Box 54)
  - Life Sciences Labs Dedication Ceremony 1987 Mar 27-28 (Box 54)
  - Local Government Attorneys of Virginia--Fall Conference 1986 Oct 4 (Box 54)
  - McIntire School Faculty 1985 Sep 3 (Box 54)
  - Medical Alumni Council 1986 Oct 7 (Box 54)
  - Mid-Atlantic Medical Library Association 1986 Oct 16 (Box 54)
  - Miller Center Award Presentation 1985 Oct 3 (Box 54)
  - The National Conference for Religious Freedom 1986 Oct 23 (Box 54)
  - New Faculty Orientation 1985 Sep 10 (Box 54)
  - New Student Convocation n.d. (Box 55)
  - New York Trip--Alumni 1985 Dec 4-5 (Box 55)
  - Orientation Week 1985 Aug 31-Sep (Box 55)
  - New York Times--Speeches and Background Materials n.d. (Box 55)
  - Parents' Weekend 1986 Oct 10-11 (Box 55)
  - Piedmont Virginia Community College 1985 Sep 16 (Box 55)
  - Resident Staff Orientation 1986 Aug 29 (Box 55)
  - Resident Staff Banquet 1985 Aug 30 (Box 55)
  - Roanoke Area Legislative Luncheon n.d. (Box 55)
  - Senior Center Luncheon 1987 Jan 13 (Box 55)
  - Staunton Rotary Club 1986 Sep 16 (Box 55)
  - SCHE--Student Outcomes Representative n.d. (Box 55)
  - Student Council 1986 Sep 23 (Box 55)
  - TGIF--Diabetes Benefit n.d. (Box 55)
  - Toastmasters International n.d. (Box 55)
  - Virginia Community Colleges n.d. (Box 55)